♪♪
You can't do this
to me, Richard.
Think of it as an
early retirement.
I'm not ready to retire.
You're ready, A.C. Believe me.
But the three of us started
this company together...
You, Marvin and I.
How can you just throw
34 years out the window?!
Your brother is dead.
And with all the good
that you've been doing
around here lately, you
might as well be dead, too.
I know I've had some problems...
It's happening, isn't it?
Richard giving him the axe.
You can't fire me!
I won't let you just toss me
out like an old newspaper!
A.C., take it easy.
I'll sue you! I'll shut
this place down...!
- Hey!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Wait!
- Stop, stop, stop, stop.
Please.
It's over.
No, it's not over.
Believe me.
I think he took that
rather poorly, don't you?
Uh-uh.
Whatever it is, it's going
to have to wait till morning.
I'm going home.
Oh, don't take this wrong, Stan,
but whatever you
want, the answer is no.
Well, that's a hell of a
way to greet your boss.
But I can understand.
I am genuinely sorry
about your vacation.
I'll make it up.
Thank you very much.
How about starting right now,
by giving these
to somebody else.
There is nobody else.
In fact...
What is this?
The Richard Wagner murder case.
Stan, the Martin trial
starts on the 18th.
Julie, we're all overworked.
But I have a dozen open cases.
Tell it to the legislature.
They're the ones
who cut the budget.
No, I recommend that
you hang onto these stocks.
They've shown steady growth
in the past three quarters.
Lieutenant, couldn't we do
this after the market closes?
I've just got a couple
more questions.
As far as you know,
did Richard Wagner
and Avery Campbell
have any arguments prior to
the one they had last night?
Richard was on
A.C.'s case a lot.
I don't know if I'd
call them arguments.
You have to understand
something, Lieutenant...
A.C. is basically a sweetheart,
but he's had some problems.
What kind of problems?
His wife died last year.
He couldn't handle it.
He became so depressed,
they had to institutionalize
him for a month.
When he finally did
come back to work,
well, he was never
really up to par after that.
How could Mr. Wagner fire him?
Weren't they partners?
Richard bought A.C.
out two years ago,
when his wife became ill.
So you see, Lieutenant, A.C.
is just a salaried employee
like the rest of us.
Now, if you don't
mind, I really do have
some very important
phone calls to make
to the West Coast, Lieutenant.
Yeah, well, I want to thank
you for your time, and, uh,
and I'll be...
in touch.
Hi.
Hi, Julie.
What you got?
I'm just about to question
Avery Campbell...
The victim's ex-partner.
- Care to...?
- Tag along?
You bet.
And you left the
building at what time?
7:15.
Now I understand that
you and Mr. Wagner
had a rather loud
argument just before that.
Yes, we did.
I-I'm not proud of my
behavior, Lieutenant.
But Richard could be...
quite aggravating at times.
Well, I understand...
he was firing you.
Yes, he was.
Mr. Campbell, where did
you go after you left last night?
Home.
Uh, I made myself some
dinner, and, uh, went to bed.
Did you talk to anybody?
Make any phone calls?
Well, I tried to call my
son, but he wasn't home.
Does anybody know
you were home all night?
I'm a widower, Miss March.
Living alone makes it hard
to come up with an alibi.
Especially when you have no
idea you're going to need one.
So you left the building at 7:15
and didn't come
back till this morning...
That what you're saying?
Yeah, that's correct... 7:15.
8:30. I saw him there at 8:30.
I know because that's
what time it always is
when I finish emptying
the wastebaskets.
That's what I was
doing when I saw him...
Emptying the wastebaskets.
And you're sure it
was Avery Campbell?
Oh, yeah, it was Mr. Campbell.
I know because whenever
he sees me he says hi.
He's a nice man.
I'm not getting him in
any kind of trouble, am I?
No, don't worry. You've
been very helpful.
And thanks.
You can go now.
Thank you very much.
Hi, Bob.
- Julie.
- Hi, Stan.
So what's this I hear about a
witness in the Wagner case?
The man who just left.
He's a custodian at
the brokerage firm.
He says he saw Avery Campbell
in his office last
night at 8:30.
Campbell told us he
was at home from 7:30 on.
Well, there you go.
When you going to file it?
Is there a problem?
I'm just not sure that Avery
Campbell is the man we're after.
Julie, the man had motive,
means and opportunity.
And he lied about
where he was last night.
Well, of course he lied.
He's afraid he'd be
accused of murder.
He was afraid he'd get caught.
Stan, we haven't even
found the murder weapon yet.
And I just can't see
that nice, little old man
as a killer.
Julie, file the indictment.
Oh, Miss March.
- Come along.
- Please, for just a moment.
I'm sorry, Mr. Campbell,
but I can't talk to you
without your lawyer present.
I know. He told
me the same thing,
but it isn't about this case.
Please?
I, uh, wanted you
to know why I lied
about being in the
building that night.
As you pointed out,
Richard was letting me go.
That must have been
very painful for you.
It was a great blow
to my pride, yes,
but that... there's
more to it than that.
You see, I'm not as well
off as you might think.
I have a son who, um,
hasn't found himself
professionally,
if you know what I mean.
You support him?
Yes. And my wife's illness
was a terrible financial
as well an emotional burden.
I have to work.
And... I lied...
Because I didn't
want anyone to know
what I was doing in
that building that night.
I was, uh, making
copies of client lists.
I thought they might
help me to get a job
with another firm.
I, uh, I just wanted
you to know.
Thank you.
Miss March, I understand
you have a recommendation
concerning bail.
Yes, I do, Your Honor.
The state would like to
recommend that bail in this case
be set at, uh, $10,000.
$10,000, Miss March?
Yes, Your Honor.
Very well. So ordered.
Next case.
- Hi.
What are you...?
Oh, these flowers.
Our dinner!
Oh, I guess we won't be having
your famous fried
chicken dinner?
Oh, Ben, oh, I'm so sorry.
I've just been so swamped.
I can barely remember my name.
Okay, we'll go out.
I don't think I have the energy.
Okay, we'll stay in.
I'll cook.
There's nothing here.
I don't even have time to go
to the grocery store anymore.
Oh, I'll scrounge
around in here.
There's bound to be something
in the back of the refrigerator.
Yes, but it's usually green.
Stanley's working you too hard.
It's not his fault.
There's just too much
work and too few people.
Anyway, I think I'm just mostly
upset about this Wagner case.
Oh.
I hear you got an indictment.
Uh-huh.
Avery Campbell,
Wagner's ex-partner.
What's the problem?
I don't know.
I just, uh...
I just feel uncomfortable
prosecuting this case.
I seem to be the only person
who isn't sure Avery
Campbell did it.
Well, you've indicted on less.
I know.
I just have this feeling.
He's such a sweet man.
You should've seen him
at the arraignment, Ben.
He was so frightened
and so overwhelmed.
Well, you've still got time.
Why don't you keep digging,
and then, if
you're not satisfied
and still don't like
it when trial comes,
you just have Stanley
give it to somebody else.
There is nobody else.
No?
You want to set the table?
What'd you find?
Oh.
Some eggs and some milk
and-and some onions
and a little piece of cheese.
Good omelet.
You're a genius.
Hello.
Oh, no.
Yes, I will.
Thank you for calling.
What's wrong?
Avery Campbell just
committed suicide.
Oh, Julie, I'm so sorry.
I... I shouldn't have let Stan
push me into filing
that indictment.
Well, you didn't know
this would happen.
No.
Yes, I did. I knew.
I knew he couldn't handle this.
I let it happen.
Julie, it's not your fault.
Julie.
Oh, morning, Bob.
Oh, hi, Ben.
What are you doing here?
Julie.
You about done?
Yeah.
Been here all night.
Comes up your
garden-variety suicide.
One shot, close
range, right temple.
Found this gun in his hand.
Oh.
This note was found
in his typewriter.
Admits killing Wagner, huh?
Says dying is preferable
to spending the rest
of his life in prison.
His son I.D.'d the gun.
Said Campbell kept it in
the top drawer of his desk.
Thanks.
Excuse me.
I'm Julie March
with the D.A.'s Office.
Paul Campbell.
I'm so sorry about your father.
I-I just don't understand.
When I saw him last
night, he seemed fine.
You were here last night?
Dropping off his car.
I borrowed it last Sunday.
He said he needed
it for a couple days,
probably just to
clean out his office,
and then I'd be
welcome to keep it.
He even said
that he'd drop it off
so I could take it to a
job interview on Friday.
I just, I just don't understand.
I'm so sorry.
Where did that come from?
Oh, just found it in the
trunk of Avery Campbell's car.
Remember seeing one just like it
in the conference room
at the brokerage house.
Think it's the murder weapon?
But Richard Wagner was
killed on Monday night.
Yeah?
Avery Campbell
didn't have his car then.
His son just told me he
borrowed it on Sunday
and didn't return
it until last night.
Yeah?
How did that candlestick
get in his trunk?
He probably put it in
there after his son left.
Julie?
I'll see you.
Julie!
Why would Avery Campbell
put that candlestick
in his car last night?
Well, I don't know.
He was gonna
get rid of it, I guess.
Why bother? He was going
to commit suicide, remember?
Well, maybe-maybe
he hadn't decided yet.
I don't think so.
The only way this
makes any sense at all
is if somebody shot him,
put the gun in his hand,
typed that note and then
planted the candlestick
in his car, not knowing that
his son had just returned it.
- Well...
- And the only person
who would've had the candlestick
is the person who really
murdered Richard Wagner.
Don't you see?
He killed Avery Campbell
and made it look like a suicide
so that everybody would
think both cases were closed.
Well, it-it sounds okay,
but it could be that
you're, you know,
just hoping and
jumping to conclusions.
Aren't you the one
who's always saying
you got to go
with your instincts?
Well, yeah.
I may have said something
to that effect once or twice.
Well, my instincts
are telling me
that Avery Campbell
did not commit suicide.
And, by George, this time
I'm gonna listen to them.
Ms. Cole?
I'm too old to be
liberated, honey.
"Miss" is fine.
Betty is even better.
Well, I'm Julie.
Julie March with
the D.A.'s Office.
May I talk to you for a minute?
Sure.
My goodness.
Mr. Wagner's
office was really...
Pretentious.
That's the word most
people used to use.
Behind his back, of course.
Ms. Cole, I under... Betty.
I understand that Mr. Wagner
was not an easy
man to get along with.
Is that true?
About as true as you can get.
So he had a lot of enemies?
Well, he sure didn't
have a lot of friends.
She's very pretty.
His daughter?
Hardly.
That's the third Mrs. Wagner.
Celeste.
Oh.
"Oh" is right.
I guess I'm lucky he didn't
trade me in for a younger model.
You were his secretary
for a long time?
Mm-hmm.
Since before the
firm even existed.
Then you must know everything
that goes on around here.
Honey, if I don't know
it, it isn't worth knowing.
I really don't understand
what it is you're
investigating, Miss March.
I thought that
A.C. had left a note
saying that he was the
one who had killed Richard.
Yes, but there are
still a few things
that need to be cleared up.
Like what?
Well, like where
you were at 9:00
on the night of the murder.
Jogging.
Do you always jog at night?
I either jog then or
go to the gym, yes.
Anything else?
I understand Avery Campbell
wasn't the only person
who'd been having problems
with Mr. Wagner lately.
Yes, I had problems
with Richard.
From the very beginning.
At first it was because
I was a woman...
Which meant, in his eyes, I
was only good for two things,
one of which was
fetching his coffee.
What about recently?
Last quarter, I
earned my clients
more money than any
other broker in this company.
I felt I deserved to
become a partner.
Richard didn't agree.
Anything else?
No, no.
I think that's all.
Good.
Because I'm about
to make my client
several thousand dollars richer.
David. Taylor.
Yes, listen.
BNX Oil just hit 27.
I want you to sell
all 5,000 shares now.
Mr. Randall!
Hi.
I'm Julie March
with the D.A.'s Office.
I was hoping you'd have
time to answer a few questions.
On my way to a lunch meeting.
Oh, well, maybe later.
What time will you be back?
I'm not really sure.
Questions about what?
Your relationship to
Richard Wagner mostly.
He was my mentor,
and I'll miss him dearly.
If you have any more questions,
my secretary will have
to set something up.
Excuse me.
Julie.
What's going on?
What do you mean?
I hear this morning
you asked for
a continuance in
the Martin case.
Yes, I need more
time to prepare.
Well, if you weren't
out harassing people,
you'd have plenty
of time to prepare.
I'm not harassing anybody.
Well, that's not what
John Randall says.
You know, frankly, Julie,
I don't understand you.
One minute, you're telling
me how overworked you are,
and the next minute
you're wasting your time,
to say nothing of
taxpayer dollars,
over a case that's
already been closed.
But it shouldn't be closed.
I'm almost positive Avery
Campbell was murdered.
Avery Campbell
committed suicide.
No, no, no.
He was murdered
by the same person
who murdered Richard Wagner.
Oh, Julie,
- will you please...
- Then why would
he commit suicide
just hours after
he insisted to me
that he was innocent?
Because the man was
emotionally unstable, that's why.
For God's sake,
look at the facts.
I have.
I have, and I'm not convinced.
Julie, I know you liked
this man Avery Campbell,
but I'm here to tell
you, once and for all,
that the Wagner and
Campbell cases are closed.
- Stan...
- You know as well as I do
that sweet little old men
commit murder every day.
Now, I want you to stop
taking these continuances
and get on with your work.
Am I clear?
Yes.
You should've seen him.
Stan?
I felt like I was
in first grade,
getting bawled out
for talking out of turn.
I got bawled out one time.
Actually, I got sent home.
We had a teacher, and one
morning she gave us a test
that was so hard
that everybody failed.
Everybody.
So a bunch of us boys got it up
that next time she turned around
at the blackboard, we was
gonna throw spitballs at her.
Well, I had, I had a big one.
Good one.
When she turned
around, I reared back
and let go.
And I was the
only one that threw.
Caught her right on the butt.
Just splat!
She knew it was me 'cause I
was the only one that was grinning.
Mama gave me a whipping.
But it was funny.
I mean, just splat,
right on the butt.
You got any napkins?
Here.
Yeah, thanks.
Want half?
Oh, no, I'm not hungry.
My mustard.
Mustard, mustard, mustard.
Just splat!
I can't believe that
John Randall called Stan.
Maybe he was upset.
I barely spoke to the man.
But he called Stan and
says that I'm harassing him.
Now why would he do that?
Does he have something to hide?
Stan doesn't think so.
Stan thinks Avery Campbell
didn't want to get fired.
Ben, what am I going to do?
This thing is making me crazy!
Well, ordinarily, I'd tell you
to do what your
heart makes you do,
but this time I can't.
Why not?
I don't want you to get
involved with a two-time killer.
Conrad isn't doing anything.
He could, he could
give you a hand.
That's very sweet of you.
If I need help, I'll ask you.
So you're gonna keep digging?
That's what you do, isn't it?
Well, yeah, yeah.
And there-there's one-one
more thing I'd do if I were you.
What?
I'd put some mustard
on that sandwich.
Yeah, yeah.
Look, I spend hundreds of
dollars a month in your shop.
I don't think it's
unreasonable for me to expect
that the flowers you deliver
to last longer than
24 hours, do you?
Good. See that you do.
Didn't your boss speak
to you, Miss March?
As a matter of fact, he did.
It was never my intention
to harass you, Mr. Randall.
I just wanted to ask
you a few questions.
Yes?
I'll have to call him
back in five minutes.
Make it quick.
I see you've taken
over Mr. Wagner's office.
You must be the new CEO.
As of last night.
Unanimous vote of
the board of directors.
As I said, Richard taught
me everything I know.
It was only natural that I
take over the company.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I-I heard things between you two
had been a little
strained lately.
Something about a big
argument around three weeks ago.
What was that about, anyway?
A couple of my clients
had taken some losses
which Richard thought
could have been avoided.
I disagreed.
It's no big deal.
So it wasn't as
though you were about
to get fired or anything.
What are you trying to suggest?!
That I killed Richard
to save my job?
That's ridiculous!
Where were you around
9:00 the night of the murder?
Oh, please, please!
I was in my car en route
to a groundbreaking party
up in, uh, Rosemead.
Did you take a date?
I think I went alone.
Oh.
Yes?
All right.
You'll have to excuse me.
It's imperative
that I take this call.
Well, thank you for your time.
And congratulations.
Things seem to have
worked out pretty well for you.
I just need you to switch
these two paragraphs, all right?
And I need it in ten minutes.
You work for
Taylor Sinclair now?
Well, don't look so
surprised, honey.
Appropriating the
former CEO's secretary
is a smart career move.
How's by you?
I just had a talk
with John Randall,
and he seems to think
everything between him
and Mr. Wagner
was just hunky-dory.
Well, I don't know whether
he's lying to you or to himself,
but believe me,
if Richard had lived, John
would be history by now.
That big argument they
had, he says it was about
a couple of bad
investments that he'd made.
No way. It was about
his coming in late,
leaving early and all those
three-hour lunches in between.
Bet on it.
May I ask you one more thing?
Sure.
Do you happen to know the name
of the florist John
Randall uses?
You planning on
sending him roses?
♪♪
- Hi.
Is this a stakeout?
Uh-huh.
Well, when did you
get into this line of work?
When I couldn't
get anybody to help.
What are you doing here?
Conrad couldn't make it.
You said he wasn't busy.
Well, he is.
What's up?
I'm going to visit John Randall.
Is he dangerous?
I don't know.
You just offered
me Conrad as a way
of checking up
on me, didn't you?
Yeah.
Are you worried about me?
Uh, a little.
Thank you.
Look!
Daggone, he's
already going inside.
That's okay.
There must be 50
apartments in this building.
He's in number 32.
How'd you know that?
Because he's had flowers
delivered there once a week
for over three months. Come on.
Hi.
Yes?
Could we speak to
John Randall, please?
There's nobody
here by that name.
Don't I know you?
I don't think so.
Uh, we-we just
want to talk to him.
I don't know any John Randall.
I remember. Your picture
was in Richard Wagner's office.
If you don't leave, I'm
going to call the police.
Now wait a minute!
You were his wife.
Let them in, Celeste.
So now you know.
More importantly, did
Richard Wagner know?
He found out about
three weeks ago.
That's what that big
argument was about.
He discovered you were
having an affair with his wife.
Doesn't change the
fact that I didn't kill him.
But it gives you
an excellent motive.
Why do you think I pushed
so hard to get you to lay off?
He's telling the truth.
We didn't plan on anything
to happen between us.
It just did.
And now your husband is dead.
And instead of
being out of a job,
your lover's running
the company.
Couldn't have worked out
better if you'd planned it, could it?
I was here the night Richard
was murdered with Celeste.
Mr. Randall, in my experience
as a defense attorney,
rarely does having your
mistress vouch for you,
and say that you didn't
murder her husband,
go over well with a jury.
You don't have to
take our word for it.
That was the night
we had a problem
with the disposal, remember?
That's right.
The manager was here till
almost 10:00 trying to fix it.
John's not very handy
around the house.
Well, they're clear.
Yep, sure are.
John Randall didn't do it.
Nope, he sure didn't.
The real killer's still
out there somewhere.
Yep, she sure is.
She say "she"?
Oh, thank you.
Pardon me.
Hi.
Well, hello there.
You're getting to be quite a
regular customer, aren't you?
I know, and I apologize,
but where would I find a
record of all the investments...
that, uh, Taylor has made
on behalf of her clients
in the last six months?
Right there.
You think you could
pull those files for me?
Wait a minute, honey.
This ought to keep
you off the hook.
A subpoena!
You like to play
hardball, don't you?
Well, batter up.
Still, I remember when you
were talking to me about it.
Taylor seems to have
put most of her clients
into Sheldrake Electronics,
Maystream Sciences and Raydyne
at one time or another.
And done very well by them.
Well, Miss Sinclair's either
very smart or very lucky
or very well-connected.
Ben!
Did you find out anything?
Plenty. Taylor's
success just might be due
to insider information.
Oh... Did you talk to SEC?
Well, I tried, but they
gave me the runaround.
It would be a lot easier to
get information if, you know,
if I had an "in" there.
You want me to call
Harry Denton, don't you?
Yes.
Oh, Julie, do I have to?
Harry Denton's your friend.
Well, yes, he is, but
every time I call him,
he invites me to dinner,
and then his wife pairs me
off with some friend of hers
who's recently widowed.
Ben, please? I just need to know
if there's any investigation
going on down there
involving Campbell,
Wagner, Campbell
or Taylor Sinclair.
Okay, I'll call him.
But you have to tell Stan
you're still on the case.
Okay.
And you tell Harry's
wife you're taken.
Julie.
Hi. Come on in.
I've been with the mayor all
day... I just got your message.
Stan, please sit down.
Now, I know I'm
on thin ice here,
but I would like your permission
to search Avery
Campbell's house again.
I don't believe
what I'm hearing.
I know you told
me to drop the case,
- Yes.
- And I tried,
believe me, but I can't.
My instincts just won't let me.
Julie...
What kind of a
prosecutor would I be
if I didn't listen
to my instincts?
I'd be terrible.
I'd do everything by rote.
It would be like throwing
all my cases into a computer.
Okay.
- What?
- I said okay.
Go to Avery Campbell's house.
What the hell,
if it's gonna help
to get this out of your
system, go to the moon.
Just go right away.
I will, tonight, on my own time.
It won't cost the
taxpayers a dime.
I'll leave the
key with Jennifer.
Tell me something.
Just what do you expect
to find there anyway?
All I know is that when
the police were there before,
they were looking at
the scene of a suicide,
not a murder.
Maybe they missed something.
Jule... this is the end of it.
♪♪
- Hello.
- Finally! Where have you been?
I can't come to phone right now,
but if you leave your
name and number
at the beep, I'll
get back to you.
Daggone, I hate these things!
Where are you?!
I knew it.
No.
Oh! Come on!
Whoa, lady, or
I'll break your arm.
How did you know I was here?
Stanley Hayden.
Would you rather have
the pair you left here...
the night you murdered
Avery Campbell?
You are going to hear
how Richard Wagner
became aware that Taylor
Sinclair was being investigated
by the Securities and
Exchange Commission.
You are going to
hear how he decided
there was only one way
he could save his company...
By firing Ms. Sinclair.
And you are going to
hear how Taylor Sinclair,
terrified that her career
was about to be ruined,
waited until Mr. Wagner
was alone in his office
and killed him
with a candlestick...
the very candlestick
Avery Campbell had been
holding earlier that evening.
And then she assumed two things:
one, his fingerprints
would be on the candlestick;
and two, since he and Mr. Wagner
had argued earlier that evening,
Avery Campbell would
be blamed for the murder.
I'm sorry to say...
she was right.
But she didn't stop there.
She knew there was
always the chance
that somebody would
discover the truth.
So she did the only
thing she could...
She murdered
Avery Campbell, too.
It must have been
relatively easy.
After all, Avery Campbell
had hired Taylor Sinclair...
he had been one of her
most ardent supporters,
and he was surely one
of her most faithful friends.
The last thing Avery
Campbell must have expected
from his protégé that night
was for her to shoot
him in cold blood.
But that is exactly
what she did.
And she did it with his gun,
one she had no doubt
seen on previous visits
to his home.
And then she went
to his typewriter,
and she calmly typed
out a suicide note,
leading everyone
who read it to believe
that Richard Wagner had
been killed out of anger,
and that Avery Campbell
had killed himself
out of despair.
It was a brilliant plan.
It even took into account
the fact that if Taylor Sinclair
were ever confronted by the SEC,
there were two people that
she could blame for everything:
Richard Wagner
and Avery Campbell,
who were dead, of course.
But that's what made it perfect.
Taylor Sinclair is a very smart,
a very successful, a very
accomplished woman.
We will show that she is also
a very cold, calculating
and efficient killer.
She is a woman
without conscience,
she is a woman
without compassion,
and, as you will soon
see, she deserves...
no compassion... from you.
Thank you.
Due to the lateness of the
hour, this court will be in recess
until 9:00 a.m.
tomorrow morning.
How long have you been here?
Long enough to know that
was a brilliant opening statement.
The jury already loves
you and hates her.
You can't... you can't
ask for more than that.
Are you free for dinner?
Yeah! Italian or Chinese?
American. My place.
Fried chicken?
With all the trimmings.
All right!
www.tvsubtitles.net